

Sales Enquiry/Helpline 1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211

Email Print

- <u>Send</u> <u>Email</u>
- Preview
- Modify



Amit Kumar Srivastava

Sr. Mobile Architect & Manager POC seeking roles in Application Design, Application Development, Solution Architecture, Technical Support, Client Relationship Management, Solution Design, Delivery Management, Agile Methodology, Subject Matter Expertise

- Current Designation: Sr Mobile Architect & Manager POC
- Current Company: Innoactive Intelligence LLP (Active.Ai)
- Current Location: Chennai
- Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Delhi / NCR
- Functional Area: IT Software Mobile
- *Role:* Solution Architect / Enterprise Architect
- *Industry:* IT-Software/Software Services
- Date of Birth / Gender: 03 Jul 1980 / Male
- Marital Status: Married
- Total Experience: 15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
- Annual Salary: Rs 0.0 Lac(s)
- Notice Period: 1 Month
- Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Software Technology]
- Address: F 402, Oxygen Apartment, Perumbakkam, Chennai 600100
- *Key Skills:* sr. mobile architect, solution architect / enterprise architect, application design, application development, solution architecture, client relationship management, solution design, delivery management, agile methodology, Machine Learning, Data Analysis

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: 5a20aea962beb4fd71Last Active: 23-Dec-19Last Modified: 18-Dec-19

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Product Architect with over 15 years of experience in end-to-end Product Engineering and Development in diverse domains such as banking and education sector

Resourceful in managing complete Product Life Cycle Management (PLC) with capabilities of defining the Product Road Maps fulfilling key requirements such as features, specifications & cost, product conceptualization, validation, testing, approval, development as per client specifications and documentation

Pivotal in building a team and developing product right from the scratch; established the small scale set up to a mid-scale organization Excellent track record of designing customized IT products for clients; skills to interface with clients, suggest viable software solutions, cultivate relations with them for securing repeat business

Effectively proposes solutions for applications covering banking and education domain; delivering the complete mobile application support from scratch to the delivery of the product

Work Experience

Innoactive Intelligence LLP (Active.Ai) as *Sr Mobile Architect & Manager POC Jul 2017 to Till Date*

Designing and building conversation mobile product leveraging power of conversation AI named Morfeus

Implementing product for various banks such as Axis, Kotak and HDFC

Administering the activities related to VR/MR design and building prototype for Fintech

Steering the Social Media channel integration for Chabot such as Facebook, WhatsApp, Skype for ensuring smooth functioning of the business Leading the development of products for assisting IOT devices such as Alexa and Google home

Assessing the scope of Machine Learning on mobile for attaining data security

Spearheading the set up & operationalization of Product Implementation, Development, Product Quality Assurance by establishing high performing teams

Currently managing a team of 5+ members and educating them on development of products

Devising strategies, objectives, vision, roadmap & milestones for successful execution of products

Identifying & analyzing defects, questionable, functions, errors, inconsistencies in software programs by executing Root Cause Analysis and troubleshooting the same to avoid further escalation

Interacting with the client's IT teams to gather, define, clarify and refine requirements; guiding the architecture and design of products

Finoculus India Pvt. Ltd as Associate Partner (VP Engineering)

Jan 2016 to Jul 2017

Built from MVP to Full Scale Product that is currently used by school across seven continents

Led the development of entire education management product including designing, managing and releasing B2C product known as 'Getskooly.com'

Successfully managed a team of 10+ members and delivered training to them on various aspects of PDLC (product development life cycle) Provided end-to-end support for applications from inception & requirement specs

Maintained strong rapport with key stakeholders / partners / vendors for successfully establishing sound business relationships

Developed product baselines; monitored & controlled product with respect to resource deployment, time overruns and quality compliance to ensure satisfactory execution/delivery of the same

Tagit India Pvt. Ltd as Sr. Mobile Architect

Nov 2007 to Dec 2015

Supervised the development of an important mobile product for Android, iOS, Windows & Blackberry mobiles namely 'Mobiex'

Pivotal in deployment of Mobiex Mobile Product for some key Indian & Singapore Banks along with administering high number of users Monitored progress of the technical aspects of Product version as per schedule / budgets, and ensured timely completion and delivery of product to the client; extended production support for applications

Led the design, documentation, implementation, and maintenance of several applications within preset time frame

Successfully defined the roadmap along with working with CTO

Headed a team of 20+ members and imparted training to them on various aspects of application development

Resolved operational and delivery challenges by providing strategic & tactical direction; participated extensively in strategic and tactical decision-making

Established best support practice models and methodologies to delivery services at 24x7

Developed competencies of teams by creating collaterals thereby building competency within the organization

^ Back to Top

Education

- UG: BCA (Computers) from School of management sciences in 2003
- PG: PG Diploma (Software Technology) from Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (CDAC) in 2004
- Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Post Graduate Program in Machine Learning

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name VersionLast Used Experience

Java, Objective C, Swift, Kotlin, Python C#, HTML5, CSS and Javascript Android, iOS, Windows, Blackberry, J2me ANT, Gradle, Jenkins, Cocoapod SonarQube and FastLane Windows, Linux and Mac-OS XMPP, GIT and SVN Visio, JIRA & Confluence Machine Learning, Data Analysis

2019 0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language Proficiency Read Write Speak

English Hindi

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

• Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Important

• Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

<u>Careers</u> - <u>About Us</u> - <u>Clients</u> - <u>Terms & Conditions</u> - <u>FAQ's</u> - <u>Contact Us</u> - <u>Report a Problem</u> - <u>Site Map</u> - <u>Resources</u> Our Partners: <u>Jeevansathi Matrimonials</u> - <u>ICICIcommunities.org</u> - <u>99acres</u> - <u>Real Estate In India</u> All rights reserved © 2019 Info Edge India Ltd.